<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>computer science - tag - Tom personal site</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/tags/computer-science/</link><description>computer science - tag - Tom personal site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh</language><managingEditor>ymlai87416@gmail.com (Lai Yiu Ming, Tom)</managingEditor><webMaster>ymlai87416@gmail.com (Lai Yiu Ming, Tom)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:04:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ymlai87416.github.io/tags/computer-science/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrade Kubernetes from 1.21 to 1.22</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/upgrade-k8s-v121-v122/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:04:19 +0100</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/upgrade-k8s-v121-v122/</guid><description>I am writing to document the upgrade process from Kubernetes 1.21 to 1.22.
Kubernetes end of life schedule
The process is same as my previous post. link.
But this time, it break many things.
Current setup I have installed some services on the cluster, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have helm installed.
Because sometimes I need to edit the yaml before applying it.
Currently, I have the following software installed:
ingress-nginx: v0.46 cert-manager: v1.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes move from docker to containerd</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/k8s-move-to-containerd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:06:20 +0100</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/k8s-move-to-containerd/</guid><description>Some good resources.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H7l48VQewmA
https://kruyt.org/migrate-docker-containerd-kubernetes/
But never remove docker from your machine!!.
In my cluster, I use it to host images to keep haproxy and keepalived running. Removing docker means you break things.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Kubernetes from 1.20 to 1.21</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/upgrade-k8s-v120/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 08:36:47 +0100</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/upgrade-k8s-v120/</guid><description>I am writing to document the upgrade process from Kubernetes 1.20 to 1.21.
Seems I am expected to upgrade Kubernetes at least semi-annually, in order to play catch up with the fast evolving versions&amp;hellip;
Kubernetes end of life schedule
Current setup 3 Raspberry pi as master node. use Keepalived for HA.
Ubuntu 20.04 LTS (arm), docker version 1.4.4-1, kubernetes version 1.20.5
1 x86_64 VM node as worker node.
Ubuntu 20.04 LTS (x86_64), docker version 1.</description></item><item><title>3 nodes Kubernetes cluster failed due to cert error</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/multi-node-k8s-failed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/multi-node-k8s-failed/</guid><description>1 year before I setup a Kubernetes cluster with 3 master nodes and 1 worker node, and today I got the following error
I don&amp;rsquo;t know that all the certs generated only have 1 year lifespan. Document says during update of cluster version should automatically update all the certs, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time&amp;hellip;
1 2 kubectl get pods --all-namespaces kubectl: Unable to connect to the server: x509: certificate has expired or is not yet valid Update process I found the following article.</description></item><item><title>Passing AWS Solution Architect Professional</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/passing-aws-solution-architect-prof/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/passing-aws-solution-architect-prof/</guid><description>Doing AWS Solution Architect Professional is like following road signs. It is intangible, it does not make you money, it does not teach you to make website. You just need to know enough to pass the exam and I advise you to take a breath first search approach to explore. The 5 domains are just nonsense. After reading them, you may ask yourself why you waste your precious life to do this.</description></item><item><title>My OSCP Journey</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/oscp-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/oscp-journey/</guid><description>I am a software engineer working in HK for 7 years, no much security background. I did work on machine code debugging to get what I want, you know when playing game and submitting homework assignment.
I know OSCP for long, when Kali was still named as BackTrack. I thought that getting OSCP was hard and somehow I was worrying if I can complete the whole course.
I have read BackTrack and play with Metasploit when I was studying Mphil.</description></item><item><title>Udacity Self Driving Car Term3</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/udacity-self-driving-car-term3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/udacity-self-driving-car-term3/</guid><description>Term 3, the final term is finished, and I want to share with you want I have learned in this term.
This term focuses on self-driving car brian:
Behavior Planning: Write a drive computer to drive, while collecting data and predict using what you have learned in Term 2 (e.g. EKF, UKF, particle filter, PID, etc…) Interlude: Lyft challenge on semantic segmentation Semantic Segmentation: To let the car know what these point clouds are, e.</description></item><item><title>Udacity Self Driving Car Term2</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/udacity-self-driving-car-term2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/udacity-self-driving-car-term2/</guid><description>Term 2 is finished, and I want to share with you want I have learned in this term.
This term focus on control, I learn how to use Kalman filter, particle filter, PID controller and MPC controller. This term requires C++ to finish but I have used it before.
In term 2, the course teaches you the followings:
Extended Kalman filter and Unscented Kalman filter When you have both lidar and radar and you want to extract the good from both of them, Kalman filter is the tool to use.</description></item><item><title>這個網站已經搬住 amazon web service</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/site-move-to-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/site-move-to-aws/</guid><description>之前個網站係我自己台主機入面, 用Digital ocean reverse proxy 返過來，但係我發覺SSL 同 WordPress 係 reverse proxy 下實在太難搞，而且Google search console 又成日報錯，所以我決</description></item><item><title>Cousera Deep Learning</title><link>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/coursera-deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://ymlai87416.github.io/blog/coursera-deep-learning/</guid><description>A friend of mine told me about this course, and I cannot believe that I can actually complete it.
For the price, It worths me 49 USD only for 5 courses. The pricing model is $49/month until your finish the specialization. I finish the course within a month.
I can say it is a steal, for $49, you can have a taste of reproducing some good papers in the deep learning fields.</description></item></channel></rss>